LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/rytc
GitHub: https://github.com/rytc
Portfolio: https://rytc.io

Ryan Capote

Software Engineer & Full Stack Developer

(949) 632-1030 Orange County, California ryan@rytc.io

Summary

A passionate self taught programmer of 10+ years with 6 years of experience in IT looking for an opportunity to bring my skills to a software development team.

Technical Skills

Programming: JavaScript, C/C++, PHP, Go **Front-End:** HTML, CSS, SASS, React

Version Control: Git, Subversion

Backend: NodeJS, Express **Database:** MySQL, MongoDB

Other: Linux/Ubuntu, Heroku, VMWare

Projects

vinyls.rytc.io

http://vinyls.rytc.io - https://github.com/rytc/vinyls

A web app I developed to display my record collection, deployed to Heroku and uses MongoDB Atlas.

Tech: NodeJS, React, Express, MongoDB

gssg

https://github.com/rytc/gssg

A custom static site generator written in Go with the purpose of generating my portfolio site from HTML and YAMI. files.

Tech: Go, Bootstrap

SuNodeKu

https://github.com/Abraham-Solis/suNodeKu

UCI Full Stack Bootcamp Group Project 2 - A Sudoku website that offers randomly generated puzzles at selectable difficulties, leaderboards, and a forum.

Tech: NodeJS, Express, MySQL

Uns' Table

https://github.com/rytc/ld49

Ludum Dare 49 game jam entry, a game about an unscrupulous merchant who orders the player to fight monsters and bring him the specific loot he's asking for.

Tech: C++, RayLib

Depar

https://github.com/rytc/ld48

Ludum Dare 48 game jam entry, a futuristic dystopian platform game.

Tech: C++, RayLib

Work History

Technical Support Engineer / Full-time

ABMX Servers - Tustin, CA Jan. 2015 to Oct 2021

- Enhanced the QA team's performance with hands-off concurrent installations by implementing networked OS installation via PXELinux, Windows Deployment Server and Clonezilla.
- Enabled support engineers and clients to make critical hardware choices by designing and implementing a system for testing and logging OS compatibility with hardware leading to fewer mistakes when designing a server for a client..
- Increased customer inquiries by researching and writing SEO content and product descriptions for the website.

Full Stack Developer / Freelance

CCSJC Security Team - San Juan Capistrano, CA Aug 2018 to Dec 2018

- Replaced spreadsheets-over-email process with a custom built web application using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL.
- Streamlined schedule creation for team leaders by providing an easy-to-use form.
- Provided easy access to the schedule by team members that can be accessed through any browser.

Customer Service / Full-time

Home Depot - Lake Forest, CA Feb 2009 to Dec 2014

- Increased customer satisfaction by learning and providing service across several departments in the store.
- Received several "Homer" performance recognition awards for customer service, meeting store metric goals, and for on-job training.

Education & Certifications

- University of California, Irvine (Feb 2022) The Coding Bootcamp, web development
- CompTIA Network+ (May 2020)
- Irvine Valley College Computer science courses in C/C++, Java, and data structures
- **Eagle Scout** (2008)
- Highschool Graduate